seabourn.com 2019-03-28

# Legal - Privacy Policy | Seabourn

This website and any mobile application linked to this privacy policy (collectively the “Sites”) is owned and operated by Seabourn Cruise Line Limited ("Seabourn"). Seabourn is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy and helping you make the most of your time on the Internet within a trusted environment. The Seabourn Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") applies to the Sites where it appears and discloses how we collect, protect, use and share information gathered about you through our Sites. If you use our Sites, you explicitly agree to the terms and conditions of the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of your use.

Information We Collect  
Site Use Information  
Information We Collect or Store Automatically as You Access and Use the Sites  
Information We Receive from Social Networking Sites or Other Third Parties  
Information You Provide to Us  
Mobile Application  
Email Promotions  
Promotions, Contests and Sweepstakes  
Child Privacy  
Access to Your Information  
Disclosing Information to Third Parties  
Affiliate Marketing Opt Out  
TSA Notice  
Your California Privacy Rights  
Security Procedures to Protect Information  
Inapplicability of Privacy Policies of any Linked Sites or Other Parties  
Changes to this Privacy Policy  
Your Comments are Appreciated

**Information We Collect**

We may collect personal information about you, for example, when you register at our website, request a brochure or video, an itinerary, deck plan or ebrochure, sign up to receive promotional materials, fill out a survey, or email or access our cruise booking application. We may also collect the information you submit through our "Chat" functions or our "Contact Us" pages. Confirmed guests checking in online will be asked to provide certain personal information. We also collect information when you purchase a product or service from the Sites.

Seabourn uses information you provide and other information we collect for our business purposes including, without limitation, to provide better service to our customers, to comply with our legal obligations, to operate and grow our business, to improve and customize the content you see, to provide the products, services or membership benefits you request, and to contact you about special promotions and new products. If you are a citizen or resident of the European Union, your rights under the General Data Protection Regulation are subject to the privacy notice applicable to residents of the European Union.

**Site Use Information**

Our web servers may collect the domain names of visitors to our site. This information may be combined with information related to other users to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed, and so forth. This information may identify you. Seabourn may use this information for a variety of purposes, including to measure the use of our site, to improve our marketing and to improve the content we offer. We may share this information with third parties. This might include tour or ship preferences of all visitors to our site, for example.

**Information We Collect or Store Automatically as You Access and Use the Sites**

We automatically collect certain type of usage information when you visit the Sites, receive Seabourn’s emails, or otherwise engage with us. For example, we use cookies, log file information, clear gifs or beacons, device recognition technologies and other similar tracking technology to better understand our Site usage information and to improve our Site and our user experience. We may use these technologies to collect the type of device you use to access our Sites, your device identifier, IP address or mobile operating system. If you use our website, we may collect information about the browser you are using. We might look at what site you came from, or what site you visit when you leave us. If you use our mobile application, we might look at how often you use the app and where you downloaded it. We may collect this information over time and across different websites, apps and devices. Third parties may also collect your personal information this way when you use the Sites. Some methods we use to collect this usage information is explained below.

To learn how to manage how we – and our vendors – use cookies and other tracking tools, and to read our **Do Not Track** policy, please click here.

_Cookies_ help personalize your online experience, such as recognizing your name when you revisit, your language and country, as well as to assist us in marketing and advertising. A cookie is a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters placed on your devices that uniquely identify your browser and let us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Site. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Some cookies are deleted once you leave our website ("session cookies"), while other cookies remain after you leave our website ("persistent cookies") so that you are recognized when you return to the website.

_Log File Information_ may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, information about your mobile device, referring/exit pages and URL’s, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Sites, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

_Clear gifs (also known as web beacons)_ are small graphic images or other web programming code that may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our customers, and can also be included in Seabourn’s e-mails, so that we can determine which e-mails from Seabourn are opened and which links or advertisements in those e-mails are clicked by recipients, and to help identify our users’ devices.

_Embedded scripts_ are a type of programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Sites such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Sites, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

_Browser fingerprinting_ includes collection and analysis of information from your device, such as, without limitation, your operating system, plug-ins, system fonts, and other data, for purposes of identifying your browser and device.

_Entity tags (“ETags”)_ are a feature of the cache of information from device browsers. ETags are an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a specific version of a resources found at a URL. If the resource content at that URL ever changes, a new and different ETag is assigned. Used in this manner, ETags are a form of Device Identifier. ETag tracking may generate unique tracking values even where the consumer blocks HTTP, Flash, and/or HTML5 cookies.

_Recognition technologies_ apply statistical probability tools to data sets in an attempt to recognize or make assumptions about users and devices. This information helps us to identify you across multiple devices that you may use, analyze and improve the Sites and present you with information based on these assumptions.

**Location Information**

We may collect precise location information from your device. This may include information about your exact location when you use our Platform. We may also collect this information in the background when our mobile applications are not in use.

When you interact with our site through various social media, such as when you login to our Sites through Facebook or other third party sites, or share our content on Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram, or other sites, we may receive information from the site including your profile information, profile picture, profile name, user ID associated with your account, country and any other information you permit the site to share with third parties. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to our website or Service.

We may also collect information about you from other third parties, for example, your family, friends and other travel companions, tour operators, data aggregators, and our partners. We may also collect information about you that is publicly available. This information may be combined with information we collect from you directly as discussed below. We use this information to better understand the demographics of our customers, to connect with you on social networks, and improve our Sites and your customer experience.

**Information You Provide to Us**

You are not required to register in order to access certain features of our site or to download our mobile app. If you send us an email, register on our site or participate in a blog or forum, we may collect the information you provide to us. Certain portions of our site are restricted to registered users or passengers with confirmed bookings. In addition, passengers with confirmed bookings checking in online will be asked to provide certain personal information.

There are several areas on the site where you may provide personal information or will be required to register to obtain access to certain online services not available to anonymous visitors. These include your My Seabourn account page, Seabourn Club loyalty program page, Booking online, Online Check-in, Book Shore Excursions, Order Gifts, Contact Us, Career Center or any of the places where you may email something from the website and Find a Travel Professional. Travel agents may register with Seabourn through the Travel Professional Center part of our site.

When you use the areas of our Sites restricted to registered users, we may collect the information including your name, address, gender, birth date, email address, Seabourn Club number, booking number, password, your telephone number, special occasion dates, leisure interests and dietary preferences, health requirements, and passport and credit card information (cardholder name, card number and expiration date) as well as emergency contact information (the name, address and telephone number of someone not traveling with you who we can contact in case of an emergency ( Profile Information").

Profile Information collected may be for yourself and those traveling with you. By providing us with the Profile Information of any third party, you are agreeing and acknowledging that you have the express right and authority to do so on their behalf. Each person whose Profile Information is linked to the same booking agrees that their information may be accessible to all others included in the booking.

Online Check-in speeds up your boarding process because information is submitted in advance. When you use Online Check-in you will be asked to provide some or all of the same information as the Profile Information. This information may be shared with governmental agencies including Customs or the Department of Homeland Security, with medical staff and with Seabourn’s personnel. We may keep your credit card and passport information on file and on our servers to enable you to make purchases on board more easily and to facilitate your boarding procedure.

You may also choose how you would like to receive information from us: by mail, email or telephone. If you send us an email or request information we will retain your email address and use it to respond to your inquiry. We may also use your email address to provide you with information about upcoming events, cruises, special offers, packages and other information about Seabourn or to provide you with information from companies with whom we have cooperative or joint marketing arrangements.

By providing personal information through this site you explicitly agree to our collection and use of that information as described in this Privacy Policy. You agree that we may use the personal information you provide to respond to your inquiries, process orders, contact you regarding customer service, let you know about products or services which may be of interest to you or to personalize our service to meet your needs or preferences. This may involve sharing certain information with our medical staff, affiliated companies or third parties, for instance, if you require a wheelchair or have dietary preferences. If while traveling with us you suffer a personal injury, or submit a claim after suffering a personal injury, we may use your personal information, including Profile Information, to provide assistance to you, assess, report, administer and manage any claims and to support our risk management policies and processes. We may share this information with third party service providers and advisers to support us in these activities.

If while traveling with us you participate in casino activities, we may collect information about your gaming preferences. We may use this information to let you know about services or promotions which may be of interest to you. We may share this information with third parties with whom we have cooperative or joint marketing agreements.

**Email Promotions**

You may subscribe to our email promotions program by registering on our website or within your account page. By using a password when registering, you are securing your subscription to receive email promotions. Emails from Seabourn may contain clear gifs, unique hyperlinks and other methods to track your engagement with the email promotions we send you. You may unsubscribe or change your email address for email promotions at any time by following the instructions mentioned within each email promotion.

**Promotions, Contests and Sweepstakes**

From time to time we may offer promotions, contests, or sweepstakes (collectively referred to as “Promotion”) on our Sites. If you choose to participate, we will collect information including your name, address, age, date of birth, telephone number and e-mail address. We may also request other information from time to time. We use the information you provide for purposes of conducting the Promotion and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. A Promotion may be sponsored by Seabourn alone, with another sponsor or by a third party. Information you provide may be shared with the sponsor or third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Certain promotions may have additional terms and conditions which will be disclosed in the promotion.

**Child Privacy**

Our sites are meant for adults. Because of the nature of our business, our products and services are not designed to appeal to minors and we do not knowingly collect information on children under 13 without parental consent. If you believe we have collected information from a person under 13 and would like the information removed, please contact us at [privacySBN@seabourn.com](mailto:privacySBN@seabourn.com). Parents, you can learn more about how to protect children's privacy on-line.

**Access to Your Information**

You are responsible for the accuracy and completeness of all information you provide to us. You may, at any time, access and make changes or corrections to your Profile Information or preferences, or delete them, simply by visiting the My Seabourn account section of the site and providing your email address and password. You may also direct us to change or delete your information by mail or email at the address provided below. You can direct us to delete your email address from our mailing list simply by following the instructions on any email you receive. We will act on your instructions promptly, but making changes or deleting information may take ten days or more to become effective.  
450 Third Avenue West, Seattle, WA 98119  
or [privacySBN@seabourn.com](mailto:privacySBN@seabourn.com)

**Affiliate Marketing Opt Out**

  * You may limit our affiliates, our sister cruise lines in the Carnival Corporation (Carnival Cruise Lines, Costa, Holland America Line, Cunard, Aida, P&O Cruises (UK and Australia) and Princess Cruises), from marketing their products or services to you based on personal information Seabourn provides them. This information includes your name, your address, and your history of cruising.
  * Your choice to limit marketing offers will apply for 5 years from when you tell us your choice. Once that period expires, you will receive a renewal notice which will allow you to limit marketing offers for another 5 years.
  * If you have already made a choice to limit marketing offers from us, you do not need to act again until you receive the renewal notice. To limit affiliate marketing offers, contact us toll free at 866-755-5619.

**Disclosing Information to Third Parties**

We may share your information with our affiliated companies of Carnival Corporation and plc including but not limited to Carnival Cruise Lines, Princess Cruises, Holland America Line, Cunard, Costa, Aida, P&O Cruises UK, and P&O Cruises Australia and third parties as described in this Privacy Policy.

  * you request or authorize it;
  * the information is provided to help complete a transaction for you;
  * the information is provided to comply with the law, applicable regulations, governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders or subpoenas, to enforce our site’s Terms and Conditions, Legal Notices or other agreements, or to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of our users or others (e.g., to a consumer reporting agency for fraud protection, etc.);
  * the disclosure is done as part of a purchase, transfer or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, customer information may be one of the transferred assets);
  * the information is provided to our agents, outside vendors or service providers to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing customer service, processing orders, sending emails about our products or services, etc.) or with whom we may have cooperative or joint marketing arrangements;
  * the information is shared with third parties for their own marketing use, or
  * to others as described in this Privacy Policy or that we may describe to you at the time of collection.

**Transportation Security Administration Secure Flight Notice**

The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth and gender for the purpose of watch list screening under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R. parts 1540 and 1560 for all commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States which is booked on or after August 15, 2009. You may also provide your Redress Number, if available. If you book commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States in conjunction with your voyage we will request this information from you and forward it to the TSA as required by law. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area. TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA privacy policies or to review the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see the TSA Web site at www.tsa.gov.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

Seabourn may disclose your personal information to our affiliates or other third parties for their use in marketing to you unless you tell us not to. In order to opt out of such sharing or for further information, please contact us at [privacySBN@Seabourn.com](mailto:privacySBN@Seabourn.com) or call 1–866-755-5619.

**Security Procedures to Protect Information**

We use reasonable means to safeguard the personal information you provide to us through the Site, but any information you provide us by email or fax is unencrypted. Data transmission over the internet is never 100% secure.

While we take steps to protect your personal information and keep it secure, you also play a role in protecting your information. You can help to maintain the security of your online transactions by not sharing your booking number or password with anyone.

**Inapplicability of Privacy Policies of any Linked Sites or Other Parties**

Seabourn’s Sites may contain links to other sites such as our affiliates and third parties. This Privacy Policy only addresses Seabourn’s use and disclosure of your information collected on Sites displaying this Privacy Policy. While we try to link only to sites that share our standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third parties or the content of linked sites, so we encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such parties or web sites.

**Storage of Information**

Information we maintain may be stored in the United States. If you live outside of the United States, you understand and agree that we may transfer your personal information to the United States. Our Sites are subject to the laws of the United States, which may not provide the same level of protections as those in your own country.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We will occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. The use of your information is subject to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use in effect at the time of use. We encourage you to check our site frequently to see the current Privacy Policy to be informed of how Seabourn is committed to protecting your information and providing you with improved content on our website in order to enhance your online cruise planning experience. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy we will post the revised Privacy Policy and the revised effective date on this site.

If you have any questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy or our website, you can contact us at [privacySBN@Seabourn.com](mailto:privacySBN@Seabourn.com). This site is owned and operated by Seabourn Cruise Line Limited which controls any information submitted through this site.

Effective Date: As of April 3, 2018

® 2018 SEABOURN CRUISE LINE LIMITED. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED
